The Duke of Burgundy is a drama, mystery, romance
film directed by Peter Strickland.
Day in and day out, lovers Cynthia and Evelyn enact an elaborate
sadomasochistic fantasy as mistress and maid.
But as their ritual of domination and submission begins to turn stale, Cynthia yearns for
something more conventional, while Evelyn tries to push their taboos even further.
Cynthia, played by Sidse Babett Knudsen.
Evelyn, played by Chiara D'Anna.
Dr. Fraxini, played by Eugenia Caruso.
Dr. Schuller, played by Zita Kraszkó.
Lorna, played by Monica Swinn.
Dr. Viridana, played by Eszter Tompa.
The Duke of Burgundy is a 2014 British erotic romance drama film written and directed by Peter
Strickland, and starring Sidse Babett Knudsen as Cynthia and Chiara D'Anna as Evelyn.
The film was screened at various film festivals, including the Toronto International Film Festival, the BFI
London Film Festival, and the International Film Festival Rotterdam, to positive critical reviews.
According to Strickland, the film was influenced by Spanish filmmaker Jesús Franco,
including with the casting of Monica Swinn, who had worked with Franco previously.
This was Swinn's first film role in over 30 years
(she had previously retired in 1982).
The film explores themes of sadomasochism, lesbian
relationship, butterfly, autumn, erotic movie.
The tone is emotional and mind_bending.